<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Julia Elman</title>
  <link href="http://juliaelman.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://juliaelman.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-10T22:20:45-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://juliaelman.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Julia Elman</name>
    <email>julia.elman@gmail.com</email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>empowering women by teaching</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2013/jan/10/empowering-women-by-teaching/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2013/jan/10/empowering-women-by-teaching</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many folks have been asking the following question: how to get more women involved in various programming communities? This questioning has led to great discussions about &lt;a href=&quot;http://pycon.blogspot.com/2012/11/survey-subsidized-childcare-at-pycon.html&quot;&gt;subsidized childcare at tech conferences&lt;/a&gt; and more focus on diversity in programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My answer: Teach women to program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night, I had the pleasure of teaching my first class for &lt;a href=&quot;http://girldevelopit.com/chapters/raleigh-durham&quot;&gt;Girl Develop It Raleigh/Durham&lt;/a&gt;. It's an affordable opportunity for women who want to learn the basics about HTML and CSS. We had about 9 students and it was... well, awesome! By the end of the class, we were laughing and learning together. The students left with smiles on their faces and telling me how much fun they had programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I learned tonight is that teaching women also empowers you as a teacher. A lot of us seasoned female veterans of programming have a lot of knowledge we can share. By getting involved and teaching other women how to program, you are not only empowering your students, but yourself too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it's like that old saying, &quot;Teach a man to fish and...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait... let's change that to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teach a woman to program and empower her for a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>an or a django template filter</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/07/11/an-or-a-django-template-filter"/>
    <updated>2012-07-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/07/11/an-or-a-django-template-filter</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I find that most projects are created out of need. You either look for something that does what you need, come up with an idea, find something that almost does what you want or both. That is how I created a new filter: anora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out by looking for a template tag or filter that would determine whether or not to us &quot;an&quot; or &quot;a&quot; based on the contextual value of a given word. Django snippets returned a tag that Chris Beaven (aka SmileyChris) created that does this based on two regular expressions: &lt;a href=&quot;http://djangosnippets.org/snippets/1519/&quot;&gt;http://djangosnippets.org/snippets/1519/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awesome, right? Yes. This is awesome. But in order to use this you'd have to double up your template context as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{ word | tag }} {{ word }}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which would result in something like this: 'an owl' or 'a raccoon'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems verbose and not very DRY (Don't Repeat Yourself). Thus, a need was found and created with anora: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juliaelman/anora/&quot;&gt;https://github.com/juliaelman/anora/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, you can simply do &lt;code&gt;{{ word|anora }}&lt;/code&gt; and 'a' or 'an' (and a space) will be added before your word based on it's phoenetic value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple, but can be very useful. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>a post post</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/jun/24/post-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/jun/24/a-post-post</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been fairly silent over the past few weeks. Some of that has been personal time and some for work. Working on something that I hope will be helpful to those of us who are at a loss about the issue of sexual harassment in the tech community. What can we really do and where do we start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pauladamsmith.com/&quot;&gt;Paul Smith&lt;/a&gt; contacted me shortly after my post with an idea his wife, Michelle, had. Why don't we create a pledge where people from the Django community can state that they will no longer attend conferences and events without a code of conduct in place? A simple form where members of the community can sign and pledge their support?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I formed a team and we got to working on what is now: &lt;a href=&quot;http://letsgetlouder.com/&quot;&gt;http://letsgetlouder.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a start and I am hoping that it gives a voice to those who want to see things change. Let's get loud and let the world know that the Django community does not agree with this kind of behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I want to say thank you. Thanks to all of you who have been supportive over the past few weeks. It has been overwhelming and humbling. I am proud to say that I am a member of the Django community, not only for the technology aspect, but for the people too.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>let's get a little louder</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/jun/3/lets-get-little-louder/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/jun/3/lets-get-a-little-louder</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A month ago, I attended a design/front end development conference. I was so excited to attend. My employer even sponsored the conference to show their support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw that a fellow Django colleague was speaking at the conference. Having attended DjangoCon and PyCon, where I knew lots of the attendees, this would be a conference in which I knew no one. It was cool to see someone from my community attending and I decided to connect with him. We caught up at the conference and talked in between sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on in the evening, a group of us headed to a post-conference social event at a local bar. My Django colleague was there as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all had some drinks and good conversation. Then, things took a turn. My colleague started making inappropriate sexual advances towards me. He singled me out and would not leave me alone, even when asked. I tried to shake it off, change the conversation and even moved away. He would not stop. I asked him what his wife would think of his behavior. He said that she would only be upset because she didn't get to watch us having sex. I then tried to change the subject completely and asked how his daughter was, thinking that would snap him out of it. And with a blank stare he said bluntly, &quot;She's a slut.&quot; I told him he should be ashamed of himself and walked away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was incredibly disappointing, humiliating and degrading on so many levels. I had been turned from a professional colleague into &quot;a hook-up&quot; at a bar. I was disgusted by his behavior, his comments about his family and the fact he is even associated with the Django community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what did I do? I did the only thing that you really can do in that kind of situation. Tell people. I went to the conference director the next day and explained what had happened. He looked at me and sighed, confessing that he never should have allowed this guy to come to the conference. He went on to ask me what I thought he should do. Wait. What? Really? He is organizing a conference and is asking me what to do? Wasn't there a policy in place for this sort of thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After these events, it is clear to me that there is a definite lack of policies and procedures in place for sexual harassment at conferences and events. What are the rules and consequences for this type of behavior? How do conference and event organizers plan on handling these types of situations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I'd like to point to a post the company I work for recently wrote. It states that they will &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caktusgroup.com/blog/2012/05/24/narrowing-gender-gap-open-source-community/&quot;&gt;&quot;require that a zero-tolerance sexual harassment policy is established and enforced by the organizers of any conference that we sponsor or attend.&quot;&lt;/a&gt; I cannot tell you how supportive they have been, even just by writing that statement. I feel that if every employer were to adopt this kind of policy, women would feel more confident in the tech community. Just knowing that your employer has got your back makes a world of difference...to anyone really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, this issue is not just about women. It's about men too. Men who want to promote having women in the tech field and are working on creating a safe and inclusive environment. It is guys like the one at the conference I spoke of, that tarnish any of the good work that has been done. I find this kind of disgusting and disrespectful behavior that I had to endure, also unfair to those hard-working people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's stop talking about apologies too. &quot;After the fact&quot; doesn't really do any good. Sexual harassment should not happen in the first place. There should be a clearly-defined set of standards in place to prevent it. Here's a few to start:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number One: If someone is known for sexual harassment or assault, or has a criminal record of doing so, don't invite them to your conference. I know that this seems like a &quot;duh!&quot; sort of thing, but I feel it needs to be stated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number Two: Create a sexual harassment policy for your conference or event. Make that policy publicly available via the conference or event website and/or program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number Three: Clearly state the consequences for these prohibited actions and post them publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, I ask other women and men in the community to share their stories. Don't be afraid to speak out. There are good people out there who feel the same way you do and want to help. Change will not come from silence. It will only begin to change if we stand up for what we know is right and get a little louder.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>reflections on imagine how creativity works by jonah lehrer</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/may/7/reflection-imagine-how-creativity-works/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/may/7/reflections-on-imagine-how-creativity-works-by-jonah-lehrer</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past April, I had the pleasure of attending &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.switchpointideas.com/&quot;&gt;Switchpoint&lt;/a&gt; in Saxapahaw, North Carolina. The conference brought together people from all walks of life. American beat poets, global health workers, an African midwife and a Kenyan tech advocate all came together in one space for one day to see what would happen. It was pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the speakers of the day was &lt;a href=&quot;http://appliedpoetics.com/&quot;&gt;Jonathan Opp&lt;/a&gt;. He spoke of branding and his experience at Red Hat and the Road Tour he helped develop. I got the chance to talk with him during the conference and how I was starting to try to draw more often. He mentioned a good book that he had recently read called, &quot;Imagine: How Creativity Works&quot; by Jonah Lehrer and highly recommend I read it. I tend to listen when smart good folks tell me to do something, and most of the time they are right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read &quot;Imagine&quot; this past weekend. The book is filled with anecdotes from various creative folks. The book has been coined as creating multiple &quot;Aha&quot; moments. It's like he is saying everything you already know, but forgot when thinking about the creativity. He speaks on the different techniques successful companies such as Pixar, 3M and Google use to foster their creative process. He mentions how the common term called &quot;brainstorming&quot; actually stifles us and keeps us from improving our projects with criticism and feedback. Towards the end he wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Here is the dis-quieting truth. Our creative problems keep getting more difficult... It's time to create the kind of culture, that won't hold us back.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now how did that apply to me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I started out as a design student. I took basic typography classes, where we had to trace over hundreds of different styles of type each night. I'd then go to a drawing class where pre-fabricated still life were lined up perfectly for us to replicate.
It was so completely boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a printmaking class as one of my art electives. It was a perfect blend of science, art and physical activity. What a thrill from the mundane &quot;design&quot; world where it seemed perfection was key! I dove head first into printmaking and gave up design.
And then, the computer lab started drawing my attention. This was the age of Napster, AIM and ease in connecting with friends all over the globe. I remember skipping my photography class so that I could spend more time in the computer lab. It was funny. I remember the design students constantly coming to me for help in figuring out how create a proper Quark layout (Yes, I said Quark.) At the time, there wasn't a &quot;web design&quot; program. HTML/CSS were just starting to become something that folks were realizing anyone could do. You didn't have to have a computer science degree in order to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my curiosity stayed with computers. I hacked around on my Compaq Presario 2286 at home and the pretty Macs at school. It was great and it was fun. Both sides of my brain were being used simultaneously with printmaking and computers. My days and nights were filled with problem solving and my brain was happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued on with my printmaking, as well as computers. I even worked as a professional printmaker while living in Los Angeles. It was an amazing experience and I even got to help pull a print from one of my all time favorite artists, Ann Hamilton. I printed an edition for Richard Serra and even contributed my own work to an inside edition that the shop did. The halls echoed of Allen Ginsberg and I heard stories of Robert Rauschenberg coming to town. I was in art school geek heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, the magic faded. I was living in a friend's living room, barely able to pay my bills and have enough food to eat. The printmaking dream just wasn't working out. So, art and I broke up. I stopped drawing and creating. I was disappointed. The break up was a bitter one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was almost 10 years ago. After the break up, I delved head first into the world of web programming. I've been fortunate to work with some of the smartest and most creative people I have ever met. I've seen and learned a lot in the past 10 years, but something has always felt off balance: Something that has been at my core ever since I was a kid drawing comic books on the weekend, pure creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, after reading &quot;Imagine&quot; and having many of those &quot;Aha&quot; moments, I am going to try to mend this part of me. Because creativity is key to each us. We all have it. Whether it's the music you've been so close to making, the book you've started writing, but never finished, or a drawing you were too pissed off to jot down. Creativity is important. It's vital to share, collaborate, adapt and create with those around you. Stop the inhibitions and the worry about making a mistake and just make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So art? Let's reconcile. I'll start by placing a new link on my site called &quot;Sketchbook&quot; and let's just see where we go from there.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>review of cosmonaut stylus</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/mar/20/review-cosmonaut-stylus-pen/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/mar/20/review-of-cosmonaut-stylus</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been looking for a way to create quick sketches digitally. Just an easy way to share, create and mock-up ideas without having touch Photoshop. After going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://gazit.me/&quot;&gt;Idan Gazit's&lt;/a&gt; talk on sketching at PyCon a few weeks ago, I was really impressed with the pen he used. He said it was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.studioneat.com/products/cosmonaut&quot;&gt;Cosmonaut created by Studio Neat&lt;/a&gt;. I decided to order it to give it a try and here is my first impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a sucker for packaging and product design. If something comes in a cool package, I'm all over it. The box that the Cosmonaut comes in is a simple light weight chip board and has all sorts of cute space stuff printed on it! The pen looks like it's ready for launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/cosmonaut1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cosmonaut stylus pen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most surprising part, was how light weight it is! From the photos and video, I thought it was going to be fairly heavy and bulky. I've got little bitty hands and was a bit worried about this. Not a problem at all. It fits perfectly in my hand and is very easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/cosmonaut2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cosmonaut stylus pen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I like about it is that the tip of the pen is pliable. It really feels like you are writing with a large felt tip pen! Very well thought out design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will note that if you are going to use this on your iPad, you might want to turn off multitasking gestures. If you like to rest your hand on your &quot;paper&quot;, this will cause issues when you are drawing on your iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I'd definetly say to give this pen a try. For $25, it's a pretty good deal. Looking forward to lots of ideas and doodles to sprout from this.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>thoughts after attending my first PyCon</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/mar/13/my-first-pycon/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2012/mar/13/thoughts-after-attending-my-first-pycon</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I was waiting outside of the Free State Brewery to meet my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adamfast.com/&quot;&gt;Adam&lt;/a&gt; for lunch. It was going to be one of the last times I got to eat there before my move to the East Coast. While burrowing into my phone while I waited, I heard a &quot;Hey Julia&quot; and looked up to see &lt;a href=&quot;http://jacobian.org/&quot;&gt;Jacob&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.frankwiles.com/&quot;&gt;Frank&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/webology/&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt;. We caught up for a bit and then the subject of attending PyCon came up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Why would I go?&quot;, I said, &quot;I mostly do front-endy kind of stuff.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Are you kidding?&quot;, said Jacob, &quot;There is going to be tons of good talk and things for you. You need to go. Seriously.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so glad I listened to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked out the conference schedule and immediately saw quite a few talks I was super interested in going to! &lt;a href=&quot;http://gazit.me/&quot;&gt;Idan Gazit's&lt;/a&gt; two talks were especially &lt;a href=&quot;http://lanyrd.com/2012/pycon/spckb/&quot;&gt;enlightening&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vfYul2E56fo&quot;&gt;motivating&lt;/a&gt; for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of my old co-workers from Mediaphormedia were there and we got to have a mini reunion in the conference hotel lobby. It was so great to see everyone, catch up on the awesome projects everyone is working on and what exciting ones are in store for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also completely amazed to see the female attendance in the crowd. It was very cool and am proud to be part of a community who is in such support of women in tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I surprised myself. I decided at the last minute to sign up for a lightning talk. I'm not a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt; fan of public speaking, but had something I felt I wanted to share with the rest of the community. Something that might be helpful to someone in the crowd. Little did I know, that my little lightning talk was being recorded and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eLuscpu4xA0&quot;&gt;streamed live through internet.&lt;/a&gt; My entire family was able to watch and cheer me on! How amazing is that? Greatly amazing. Very great indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, sitting in the airport, I find myself thinking about all of these things and where to go from here. I only have one answer to give you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let's make some cool shit.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>sometimes the best thing you can do is walk away</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2011/dec/14/sometimes-best-thing-you-can-do-walk-away/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2011/dec/14/sometimes-the-best-thing-you-can-do-is-walk-away</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's late. Way too late for anyone who consistently wakes up somewhere between 5-6am regardless of what day of the week it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the heck am I up so late you ask? I've got some coding problems I am trying to solve and can't go to sleep till they are completed! Dag nabbit and harumph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But do I really need to sit here, loosing sleep and scratching my head trying to find/Google the answer? Lately, I am finding the best thing to do when you are heading down the coding rabbit hole is to walk away. That's right. Get out of your seat, take a walk and away from your computer. I find whenever I do this, I come back to my seat feeling refreshed and get my work done faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next time you are finding yourself stuck on a problem that doesn't seem to want to get solved... walk away. You'll probably find the answer when you get back.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>simple set-up of your django project files</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2011/aug/20/simple-set-up-of-your-django-project-files/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2011/aug/20/simple-setup-of-your-django-files</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like organization. Keeping things clean, simple and easy to find make for a seamless work flow and helps to keep everyone in sync when working on a team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am constantly working on improving the way I set-up my projects file structure. Here is how I try to keep things clean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='html'&gt;myproject/
    apps/
        django-showcase/
    dev/
        __init__.py
        admin.py
        manage.py
        settings.py
    static/
       images/
       stylesheets/
       scripts/
    templates/
    urls.py&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;First up, is the top level folder name of your Django project. I'm calling this one &lt;code&gt;myproject&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is your apps folder. This is where you will keep your various Django applications that help make your site run. For example, I've included my application &lt;code&gt;django-showcase&lt;/code&gt; inside of this folder, as I use it on my site. Also, don't forget to add your applications into your &lt;code&gt;settings.py&lt;/code&gt; file under the &lt;code&gt;INSTALLED_APPLICATIONS&lt;/code&gt; list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now moving onto the most important part of my organization is the dev folder. This is where all of my development files are located, hence the name dev. Inside of here you'll see the magically important &lt;code&gt;__init__.py&lt;/code&gt; and other files that help make the other magic parts of Django run. I do this so that I don't have any floating files hanging out in my project. To make this work correctly, you'll need to make sure to set your &lt;code&gt;DJANGO_SETTINGS_MODULE&lt;/code&gt; to this folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; is the folder where all of my static media is stored. So all of my front-end stylesheets, images and scripts go here. You'll need to set the path to this folder in &lt;code&gt;settings.py&lt;/code&gt; file under &lt;code&gt;STATIC_ROOT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;templates&lt;/code&gt; folder is where all of the custom templates for your site will live. You'll also need to define where this is in your &lt;code&gt;settings.py&lt;/code&gt; under your &lt;code&gt;TEMPLATES_DIRS&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, my &lt;code&gt;urls.py&lt;/code&gt; configuration file. I place this outside of the dev folder mainly because it might cause issues if there are specific urls tied to various applications in my apps folder. A lot of reusable applications have their own url configuration files inside of them. By making &lt;code&gt;urls.py&lt;/code&gt; a top-level file, it can access those other urls and make it the main &quot;hub&quot; for your sites url structure. You'll need to set the path for your &lt;code&gt;ROOT_URLCONF&lt;/code&gt; to point here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a super simple way to organize your files using Django. Overall, the most important thing is that you use a method that easiest for you and/or your team to be most efficient in your production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the Django &lt;code&gt;settings.py&lt;/code&gt; various options, check out the docs at:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/topics/settings/&quot;&gt;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/topics/settings/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>django-showcase</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2011/aug/15/django-showcase/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2011/aug/15/django-showcase</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been meaning for a while now to get this app up and running on Github. It's a pretty simple, light weight app whose primary purpose is to serve as a base skeletal structure for a showcase of the users work. It can be used for writing samples, photos or almost anything else you'd like to showcase!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/juliaelman/django-showcase&quot;&gt;django-showcase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on building this out more and making the templates more robust. There are a few ideas that I have, but suggestions are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>and away we go...</title>
    <link href="http://juliaelman.com/blog/2011/may/20/and-away-we-go/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://juliaelman.com/blog/2011/may/20/away-we-go</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been a long time in the making, but it's finally here. My website re-design! (insert trumpets blaring here)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 2 design rounds, I finally decided to go with simple and clean. Over my many years of design I find that is always the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another part of this whole get-up that I am completely proud of, is the fact that I built out a few things completely by scratch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;a portfolio app for my work pages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;building out my own slice, running on Ubuntu 10.04 (Lucid), Apache, Django, PostgreSQL&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So, I'll pat myself on the back about that, but I am still not 100% happy. This Summer I plan on making my site my labratory (muah, ha, ha) to play around with and HAVE FUN! Because that's what being in this business is all about, isn't it? Learning new things and building cool sh*t.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>